同人市二零二二年初中毕业生学业统一考试英语听力。听力一。温馨提示：听力。一共四个部分。分别听完这四部分的材料后，先将各部分的试题在第一卷上选做出来。等包括听力二在内的听力材料全部结束后，再将答题卡。马上与各小题的所选答案对应的答题框涂黑。第一部分：看图听五个句子，选择与所听句子内容相符的图片，并在答题卡的相应位置。将其字母序号涂黑。每个句子读两遍。每个句子读完后，分别有五秒钟的答题时间。
1. We Chinese celebrate the Dragon Boat Festival every year.
2. I would like to go to the Great Wall for summer holidays.
3. As we know, October 1st is the National Day of China.
4. Beijing Opera is an important part of Chinese culture.
5. Pandas only live in China.
They are very cute.
第二部分，听五个句子，分别选择其相应的应答语，并在答题卡的相应位置。指将其字母序号涂黑。每个句子读两遍。每个句子读完后，分别有五秒钟的答题时间。
7. My mother had a bad cold, so I have to look after her at home.
8. How do you like living in Tongren?
9. I wish you success.
10. Thank you for telling me so much.
第三部分：听下列五段对话，根据对话内容及各题的问题，选择正确选项并在答题卡的相应位置将其字母序号涂黑。每段对话读两遍，每段对话读完后分别有十秒钟的答题时间。
12. Is this your English book, Linda?
Q. Whose English book can it probably be?
13. you? 13.
Hello, Kang how can I get to Jin Jiang Hotel?
Hello, Mary, go straight this road to the end.
You can't miss it on your right.
Where does Mary want to go?
Hello, Kang, Jiang 16.
Tom, what does your mother look like?
She has long hair.
15. What does Tom's mother look like?
15. What day is it today?
It's Saturday. Question.
What day is it tomorrow?
第四部分：听下面一篇短文，根据短文内容和所提问题，选择正确答案，并在答题卡的相应位置将。及字母序号涂黑。短文读两遍，短文读完后有六十秒钟的答题时间。
Dear younger sisters and brothers, as we all know, English is used very widely in
the world. How can we learn it well?
Here are my suggestions.
First, we should often listen to the tapes, English songs, and programs.
Watching English movies is also helpful to us.
Second, we are supposed to speak English in class as much as possible.
Don't be afraid of making mistakes.
The more you speak, the fewer mistakes you'll make.
We can join the English club and practice with others.
Third, we had better read more English newspapers and magazines.
It's good for us.
At last, it would be better if we can recite some good passages and keep diaries.
And a word.
As long as we do more listening, speaking,
reading, and writing, we will learn English well.
Dear younger sisters and brothers, as we all know, English is used very widely in
the world. How can we learn it well?
Here are my suggestions.
First, we should often listen to the tapes, English songs, and programs.
Watching English movies is also helpful to us.
we are supposed to speak English in class as much as possible.
Don't be afraid of making mistakes.
The more you speak, the fewer mistakes you'll make.
We can join the English club and practice with others.
Third, we had better read more English newspapers and magazines.
It's good for us.
At last, it would be better if we can recite some good passages and keep diaries.
a word. As long as we do more listening, speaking, reading, and writing, we will
learn English well.
Thank you. 71 and 75.
听力二。各位考生请注意，本部分试题在卷二七十一至七十五小题。各位考生请注意，本部分试题在卷二七十一至七十五小题。听下面一篇短文，根据所听到的短文内容填写表格，每空一词。答案务必书写在答题卡卷二各小。规定的位置。短文读两遍。
75. The year 2020 was unforgettable for everyone.
We were at home for a long time because of the COVID -19, but many people still went
out and helped people in need.
Zhongnan Shan is one of them.
This year, we can always hear his name on TV.
On August 11, Chairman Xi Jinping gave him the Medal of the Republic to thank him
for his hard work.
Zhongnan Shan is a very famous doctor.
comes from a family of
His parents are both doctors.
When he was young, his dream was to be a
He was 84 years old this year, but he still went to Wuhan and helped the people
there. During that time, he visited patients every day.
When his family called him, he always said, Don't worry about me.
I am healthy.
We should learn from him and help the people around us.
He is a hero of China.
We all thank him for what he has done for us.
The year 2020 was unforgettable for everyone.
We were at home for a long time because of the COVID -19,
but many people still went out and helped people in need.
Zhongnan Shan is one of them.
This year, we can always hear his name on TV.
On August 11, Chairman Xi Jinping gave him the Medal of the Republic to thank him
for his hard work.
Zhongnan Shan is a very famous doctor.
He comes from a family of
His parents are both doctors.
When he was young, his dream was to be a doctor.
He was 84 years old this year, but he still went to Wuhan and helped the people
there. During that time, he visited patients every day.
When his family called him, he always said, Don't worry about me.
I am healthy.
We should learn from him and help the people around us.
He is a hero of China.
We all thank him for what he has done for us.
听力考试到此结束。
Thank